<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects on Marian L. Schmidt</title>
    <link>/marschmi.github.io/project/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Projects on Marian L. Schmidt</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 25 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/marschmi.github.io/project/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>FEMMES E-Board</title>
      <link>/marschmi.github.io/project/femmes/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/marschmi.github.io/project/femmes/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Since 2015, I have been an active executive board member for &lt;strong&gt;F&lt;/strong&gt;emales &lt;strong&gt;E&lt;/strong&gt;xcelling &lt;strong&gt;M&lt;/strong&gt;ore in &lt;strong&gt;Math&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;S&lt;/strong&gt;cience and &lt;strong&gt;E&lt;/strong&gt;ngineering or FEMMES for short. My specific role in this organization is the data analyst and data manager. For this role, I lead the collection of pre- and post-event survey data from the 200 girls who attend our capstone event.  After collection and data curtation, I analyze the data from our semesterly capstone events to see if our organation is reaching our mission and to gain key data to help us write grants and improve future events.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;FEMMES is a University of Michigan student group that is promotes the involved of 4-6th grade girls in STEM by building curiosity and increasing confidence in girls&amp;rsquo; academic skills so they may purue their dreams for science without hesitation. FEMMES uses female role models to demonstrate how women can, and do, excel in these fields. The genuine passion our volunteer students, staff, and faculty have for their chosen fields inspires young participants at a critical developmental stage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We host two types of events:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1 day capstones:&lt;/strong&gt; 200 4-6th grade girls come to the Unviersity of Michigan once a semeseter to participate in 4 hands-on STEM related activities. During the day the get to interact with undergraduate and graduate students, post-docs, staff and faculty and do cool projects to get them excited about science, technology, math, and engineering.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;After school activities:&lt;/strong&gt; We go to schools and host one hands-on learning activity with girls through an after school program that we organize about once a month.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;more-information-on-femmes-can-be-found-on-the-a-href-https-www-femmes-studentorgs-umich-edu-university-of-michigan-femmes-website-a&#34;&gt;More information on FEMMES can be found on the  &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.femmes.studentorgs.umich.edu/&#34;&gt;University of Michigan FEMMES website&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/h3&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Software Carpentry Mentor &amp; Instructor</title>
      <link>/marschmi.github.io/project/swcarpentry/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/marschmi.github.io/project/swcarpentry/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I am the co-chair of the mentoring subcommittee and an instructor for the Software Carpentry organization. Software Carpentry&amp;rsquo;s mission is to increase programming and bioinformatics literacy through 2-day workshops which cover various programming languages such as &lt;code&gt;unix&lt;/code&gt;,&lt;code&gt;git&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;R&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;python&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;SQL&lt;/code&gt;, and &lt;code&gt;matlab&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As &lt;strong&gt;co-chair of the mentoring subcommittee&lt;/strong&gt;, I host monthly subcommittee meetings to try to find ways new ways to expand ways to support, mentor, and create a network of instructors across the globe. In addition, I host instructor discussions with soon-to-be instructors and instructors who will teach or have recently taught a workshop. These discussions are a great way to meet other instructors across the globe, learn about challenges when teaching workshops (and how to prepare or fix them), and to learn new pedagogies for teaching bioinformatics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More details on the mentoring subcommittee can be &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/carpentries/mentoring&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;found here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have co-taught 7 workshops and helped out at 1 workshopincluding:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2017&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;October: &lt;strong&gt;Co-Instructor&lt;/strong&gt;, University of Michigan &lt;a href=&#34;https://umswc.github.io/2017-10-16-umswc/ &#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Open workshop&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Co-taught with science librarian extraordinaire, Scott Martin.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;September: &lt;strong&gt;Lead-Instructor&lt;/strong&gt;, Ghent University &lt;a href=&#34;https://marschmi.github.io/2017-09-14-gent-cmet/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Center for Microbial Ecology and Technology&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Co-taught with two fellow microbial ecologists  Dr. ir. Frederiek-Maarten Kerckhof and Ruben Props.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;January: &lt;strong&gt;Co-Instructor&lt;/strong&gt;, University of Michigan &lt;a href=&#34;https://umswc.github.io/2017-01-17-UMich/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Department of Microbiology workshop&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Co-taught with my PhD committee member, Dr. Pat Schloss.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2016:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;October: &lt;strong&gt;Co-Instructor&lt;/strong&gt;, University of Michigan&lt;a href=&#34;https://umswc.github.io/2016-10-27-umswc-hg/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Department of Human Genetics&lt;/a&gt;. Co-taught with the two amazing early career scientists: Akima George &amp;amp; Dr. Marc Sze.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;October: &lt;strong&gt;Co-Instructor&lt;/strong&gt;, University of Michigan&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/arthur-e/2016-10-17-EEB-SNRE&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Joint Ecology &amp;amp; Evolutionary Biology &amp;amp; School of Natural Resources and Environment workshop&lt;/a&gt;. Co-taught with the very talented K. Arthur Endsley.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;January: &lt;strong&gt;Lead-Instructor&lt;/strong&gt;, University of Michigan&lt;a href=&#34;http://umswc.github.io/2016-01-04-wise-umich/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Women in Science and Engineering Workshop&lt;/a&gt;. Co-taught with brilliant first-time instructors Alix Keener, Akima George, and Dr. Ginger Allington.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2015&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;October: &lt;strong&gt;Co-Instructor&lt;/strong&gt;, University of Michigan&lt;a href=&#34;http://umswc.github.io/2015-10-19-UMich/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Department of Human Genetics&lt;/a&gt;. Co-taught with the skilled programmer, Michelle Berry.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;May: &lt;strong&gt;I became a certified Software Carpentry Instructor&lt;/strong&gt; after participating in an eye-opening and informative training with Dr. Greg Wilson and Dr. Tracy Teal.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;January: &lt;strong&gt;Helper&lt;/strong&gt;, University of Michigan&lt;a href=&#34;http://danabauer.github.io/2015-01-05-wise-umich/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Women in Science and Engineering Workshop&lt;/a&gt;. This was my first ever Software Carpentry workshop!&lt;br /&gt;




&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Teaching Consulting &amp; Instructional Technology</title>
      <link>/marschmi.github.io/project/crlt/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/marschmi.github.io/project/crlt/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Since September 2016, I have been a teaching consultant with the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.crlt.umich.edu/&#34;&gt;Center for Research on Learning and Teaching (CRLT)&lt;/a&gt;. I have two types of positions with CRLT:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Graduate Student Instructor Consultant (GSIC):&lt;/strong&gt; In addition to our monthly consulting circles/meetings, I also perform personal consultations. Each semester I work with graduate student instructors across various departments to help them with teaching and learning in their classroom. This type of consultation is called &lt;em&gt;midterm student feedback&lt;/em&gt; or MSF and has four stages. First, a pre-meeting with the instructor to see how things in their classroom are going. Second, a classroom observation and chat with the students about their learning. Three, creation of a formalized report based on the data and observations I had in the classroom visit. And fourth, a reflective post-meeting where I present the instructor with the formal report and provide a space to think about their classroom moving forward for the rest of the semester.&lt;br /&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bosses: Dr. Nicole Tuttle &amp;amp; Dr. Stephanie Moody&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Instructrional Technologist:&lt;/strong&gt; Working with my colleagues, I help to develop and teaching workshop on integrating technology, informed by pedagogy, into the classrooms of University of Michigan instructors. I help to host one workshop per semester and a few workshops during the &lt;a href=&#34;http://ttc.iss.lsa.umich.edu/ttc/enriching-scholarship/&#34;&gt;Enriching Scholarship week&lt;/a&gt; that happens during the first week in May every year at U of M.

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Boss: Dr. Ronit Ajilen.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As an instructional technologist GSIC with CRLT, I have helped to develop and teach 5 workshops related to teaching and technology, including:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;“Teaching with Technology: Incorporating Digital Media”&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;“Everyday Technology in Teaching”&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;“Let’s make a screencast with Jing”&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;“Teaching with Technology: How can I include all students?”&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;“Canvas for Graduate Student Instructors”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
