<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects on Marian L. Schmidt</title>
    <link>/marschmi.github.io/project/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Projects on Marian L. Schmidt</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 25 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/marschmi.github.io/project/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>FEMMES E-Board</title>
      <link>/marschmi.github.io/project/femmes/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/marschmi.github.io/project/femmes/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Since 2015, I have been an active executive board member for &lt;strong&gt;F&lt;/strong&gt;emales &lt;strong&gt;E&lt;/strong&gt;xcelling &lt;strong&gt;M&lt;/strong&gt;ore in &lt;strong&gt;Math&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;S&lt;/strong&gt;cience and &lt;strong&gt;E&lt;/strong&gt;ngineering or FEMMES for short. My specific role in this organization is the data analyst and data manager. For this role, I lead the collection of pre- and post-event survey data from the 200 girls who attend our capstone event.  After collection and data curtation, I analyze the data from our semesterly capstone events to see if our organation is reaching our mission and to gain key data to help us write grants and improve future events.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;FEMMES is a University of Michigan student group that is promotes the involved of 4-6th grade girls in STEM by building curiosity and increasing confidence in girls&amp;rsquo; academic skills so they may purue their dreams for science without hesitation. FEMMES uses female role models to demonstrate how women can, and do, excel in these fields. The genuine passion our volunteer students, staff, and faculty have for their chosen fields inspires young participants at a critical developmental stage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We host two types of events:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1 day capstones:&lt;/strong&gt; 200 4-6th grade girls come to the Unviersity of Michigan once a semeseter to participate in 4 hands-on STEM related activities. During the day the get to interact with undergraduate and graduate students, post-docs, staff and faculty and do cool projects to get them excited about science, technology, math, and engineering.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;After school activities:&lt;/strong&gt; We go to schools and host one hands-on learning activity with girls through an after school program that we organize about once a month.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;more-information-on-femmes-can-be-found-on-the-a-href-https-www-femmes-studentorgs-umich-edu-university-of-michigan-femmes-website-a&#34;&gt;More information on FEMMES can be found on the  &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.femmes.studentorgs.umich.edu/&#34;&gt;University of Michigan FEMMES website&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/h3&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Software Carpentry</title>
      <link>/marschmi.github.io/project/example-external-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/marschmi.github.io/project/example-external-project/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
